

### About -

With over 20 years industry experience, I specialize in Full-stack development of ES6 Node/React Javascript frameworks. I can work in front-end and back-end development and therefore lead a project from design, through to launch. I excel at finding software solutions to business problems. A full stack developer with extensive abilities in web application development, data modelling, database design and integration.

Excellent analytical skills and commercial awareness combined with the knowledge to handle the entire software development life cycle. Skilled in translating business requirements into technical solutions. Committed to quality, usability, security and scalability. I have designed software solutions driving continuous improvement to processes, systems, work ow and responsiveness. Great knowledge and working experience of software project methodologies.

#### Skills React / Redux / Storybook Serverless AWS / Lambda Node Typescript REST / API GraphQL TDD

#### **Experience**

Codegazer (self employed) Senior Javascript Developer February 2020 to August 2020

### Node GraphQL AWS Serverless Lambda Typescript React

- Refactor existing code source based on best-practices & standards.
- Writing reusable, testable, and efficient code. • Well-practiced Test driven development.
- Design and implementation of low-latency, high-availability, and performant applications.
- Implementation of security and data protection.
- Integration of data storage solutions.

#### KFC Western Europe Javascript Software Developer February 2019 to November 2019

### Node React AWS Serverless Lambda Postgres Redis Typescript

related tools to support those systems. Develop internal applications to allow for digital orders placed through 3rd party integrations. • Ensure data integrity between systems through integration layers.

Develop and design integrations between our digital ordering systems, point of sale system, payment solutions and

- Migrated legacy codebase (Heroku) into new AWS Technical Architecture that supported a new digital
- transformation project whilst maintaining high availability for existing services with a broad scope that included frontend, backend, POS systems and Salesforce. • Design and develop new user-facing and backend features.
- Develop specications and designs for complex applications whilst modifying/maintaining complex existing applications. • Perform code analysis, requirements analysis, identication of code metrics, system risk analysis and software
- reliability analysis.
- Performance tuning, improvement, balancing, usability, testing.
- Design and develop backend services and structure.

### Pregin

Javascript Software Developer November 2018 to February 2019

## Node React Redux Typescript ElasticSearch

Develop and enhance the main front end platform - website. Design and develop new user-facing features.

- Develop specications and designs for complex applications or modifying/maintaining complex existing applications. • Perform code analysis, requirements analysis, identication of code metrics, system risk analysis and software
- reliability analysis. Performance tuning, improvement, balancing, usability, testing.

### MelodyVR

Javascript Software Developer November 2018 to February 2019

### Node React Redux AWS Serverless Lambda Typescript Develop/Design/Build a fullstack integration for a Content Management System using Node/React in AWS/Serverless.

Integration of data storage solutions. • Build efficient, testable, and reusable modules and classes. Conduct testing and deploy into production.

- Contribute to planning/concept/design of information architecture.
- Design and Develop React JS front-end application CMS.
- Provide technical support to the team during the devlopment of the application solution.
- Determine business requirements and translate into component architecture within a limited timescale.
- Determine front-end application architecture. Initial integration into a AWS Cognito SDK using React/Redux Sagas pushing to CircleCI/AWS pipeline.
- Design/Develop CMS for company use. Semantic UI interface with React, immutable, redux sagas, jest/enzyme unit testing.

Big Clever Learning Javascript Software Developer April 2017 to November 2017

## Node React Redux AWS Koa MicroServices Typescript OpenAPI Spec

Develop a series of microservice application architecture counselling applications. Solve complex performance problems and architectural challenges.

- Integration of data storage solutions.
- Build efficient, testable, and reusable modules and classes.
- Conduct testing and deploy into production. Updating, repairing, modifying and developing legacy code and generic applications.
- Contribute to planning/concept/design of information architecture. Contribute and add to Node microservices API, add libraries and develop functionality.
- Run environments through Docker containers and local services. • Develop components for React applications for counselling services.
- Build components to detailed specications. Congure payment services, webhooks to Stripe. Build database schemas. Jest/Mocha mock/dontMock unit testing. Redux/Redux Saga middleware.

#### PHP / Javascript Software Developer October 2016 to March 2017

Futurebrand

### Craft PHP JQuery Ajax Develop and integrate OAuth services for global clients and further develop functionality for administration

components. Build efficient, testable, and reusable modules and classes. Solve complex performance problems and architectural challenges, SAML & OAuth integration.

• Integration of data storage solutions. • Conduct testing and deploy into production.

global clients.

• Updating, repairing, modifying and developing legacy code and generic applications. • Contribute to concept/pitching digital experiences for brands & agencies.

• Build Craft CMS PHP plugins to extend functionality of administration system for asset management services for

Purple Bridge Publishing Group Senior Developer / Team Lead January 2015 to September 2016

# Laravel PHP JQuery Ajax DevOps MySQL

Develop and lead dev team. Typical LAMP stack. Server congurations and pipeline setup, Docker containers. TDD Unit testing with PHPUnit. Design, develop, test, support and deploy custom web applications. Design and develop testing and maintenance procedures and activities. Assist and support junior team members on multiple projects. Implement best practices, standards and procedures. Develop and document design, source base and architecture. Maintain and manage existing code bases. Design, develop and implement solutions to user's needs and requirements.

• Write, review and improvise code.

with all the major services in AWS.

your own solutions on AWS.

- Coordinate with directors and business analysts to determine functionalities. • Design and develop technical solutions to complex business problems.
- Design and develop data analysis solutions. • Design and develop logical and physical data models that meet application requirements. • Design, build and deploy web services including API, databases, websites and office management software.
  - Education

# With its strong focus on solving real-world problems through problem-based learning, this BSc delivers world-class,

**BSc Computer Science** 1990 - 1993

**AWS Accreditation** 

Associate

University College London

computer science graduate, and prepares you for employment in a wide variety of industries.

industry-relevant teaching. The programme provides the essential material employers expect from a top-quality

Develop, deploy and debug cloud-based applications using AWS. Practical, hands-on skills for successfully developing

AWS Certified Developer - Associate December 2019 February 2020

AWS Certified Solutions Architect -

AWS Accreditation

Thorough understanding how to make decisions between products and services on AWS, and how to begin architecting

December 2019 February 2020

Marc Lally - marc.lally@gmail.com © Copyright 2020